Guide to the Community Service Society Archives
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series XIV, Files, 1939-1960
  - Subseries XIV.1: Files, Alphabetic
    - Studies, Internal (Box 390)
      - "Searchlight on New York", Minutes of Conferences, 1958-60 (Box 392)
      - "Searchlight on New York", Miscellaneous (Box 392)
      - "Searchlight on New York", Outlines and Plans 1958-59 (Box 392)
      - "Searchlight on New York", Publicity, Sampling of Comments 1960 (Box 392)
      - "Searchlight on New York", Questionnaire Replies (Box 392)
      - "Searchlight on New York", Reports, 1960 Internal and Public (Box 392)
      - Survey of CSS 1949 Booz, Allen and Hamilton Reports Vol. I with Separate Recommendations; Vol. II (Box 392)
      - Survey (Hundredth Anniversary) Report to Survey Com. by Otto Pollak on Objectives, Methods, etc., of the Agency (Box 393)
      - Survey of CSS 1949 Report of 10Oth Anniversary (Box 393)
      - Survey Com. to the Board (Acceptance of Report and Decision to Set up Committee on Plan and Scope to Implement It, Follow-up Report on Recommendations, 1959) (Box 393)
      - Ward Manor Houses, 1958 Public Health Nursing, 1959 Public Affairs 1959 (Box 393)
      - Youth Bureau 1959 (257 pp.) (Box 393)
    - Tax Exempt Status, 1949, 1956 (Box 393)
    - Times (N.Y.) Neediest Cases Appeal (Box 393)
    - Tompkins Square House (Box 393)
    - History by a Resident, 1968 Discussion of by Ollie A. Randall, 1940 (Box 393)
    - Tompkins Square House (Box 394)
    - Memorabilia Album Complied by Mary W.A. Weiss, Supt., 1947-1953 (Box 394)
    - Truancy Study, Family Service Dept 1944 (Box 394)
    - Trustees and Corporate Members: Dinners 1950-59 (Box 394)
    - Trustees, General (Box 394)
    - Trustees, Interviewed on Fund Raising, 1951 (Box 394)
    - United Charities Building, Correspondence, Documents, Clippings, 1890-1919 (Box 394)
    - Vacation Services: (Box 395)
      - Bungalow Hill Annual Reports 1952-59 (Box 395)
      - Bungalow Hill, General 1936-59 (Box 395)
      - Camp Fees (Box 395)
      - Camp Freedom (AICP) 1937 (Box 395)
      - General: Annual Reports 1946-47 (Box 395)
      - Health Examinations (Box 395)
      - Miscellaneous 1939-61 (Box 396)
      - Overhi11 Camp (Box 396)
      - Professional Advisory Committee on Camps 1953 (Box 396)
      - Review of Program 1951-58 (Box 396)
      - Sea Breeze Camp "History" 1949 Description 1959 (Box 396)
      - Sea Breeze Camp Legal and Property Matters 1953-60 (Box 396)
      - Sea Breeze Camp Nursing Program (Box 396)
      - Sea Breeze Camp Reports, I- 1949-55, II- 1955-60 (Box 396)
      - Sea Breeze Camp Sale 1960-1961 (Box 397)
      - Snug-in-the-Woods Camp (Box 397)
      - Statistics 1948-53 (Box 397)
      - Sunset Lodge Camp, Miscellaneous 1954-59 (Box 397)
      - Sunset Lodge Reports 1953-59 (Box 397)
    - Volunteers
      - General, 1936 (C.O.S.) - 1959 (Box 397)
      - Junior League - CSS Project 1955-56 (Box 397)
      - Workroom (Box 397)
    - War-Related Activities (Box 397)
    - CSS 1942 ff (Box 397)
    - COS-AICP 1915-18 1898 (Box 397)
    - Ward Manor Residences Annual Reports 1927, 1928, 1935 1953-54 (Caution: Some Real Names): (Box 397)
    - Ward Manor Residences: (Box 398)
      - Funds, 1926, 1940, 1940 (Box 398)
      - General (Box 398)
      - Miscellaneous 1925-60 (Box 398)
      - Rates 1946-58 (Box 398)
      - Sale and Divestment (Box 398)
      - Miscellaneous 1951-57 (Box 398)
      - Sale and Divestment (Box 399)
      - Contacts with Representative of Ward Family 1951-59 (Box 399)
      - Crugers Island 1955-60 (Box 399)
      - Catholic Charities Correspondence 1959-60 (Box 399)
      - Study of, 1951 (Russell Kurtz) (Box 399)
      - Survey and Appraisals 1957-63 (Box 399)
    - Ward, Mr. and Mrs. William B. - Correspondence and Reports, 1932-40 (Box 399)
    - Welfare: Public and Voluntary Welfare in New York City, from 1657 to the Present by Alice D. Taggart, 1960 (Box 399)
    - Welfare Council (Later Community Council) 1953-57 (Box 399)
    - Borough Councils, 1956-57 (Box 399)
    - Planned Parenthood Controversy 1953 (Box 399)
    - Clippings 1953 (Box 399)
    - Social Service Exchange, 1942 ff (Box 399)
    - Western Queens Nursery School, 1942-47 (Box 400)
    - Women's Council (Box 400)
    - Executive Committee and Women's Committee 1950-60 (also see in Minutes) (Box 400)
    - Membership List 1956 Annotated (Box 400)
    - Spring and Fall Meetings 1951-59 (Box 400)
    - Youth Bureau and Predecessors (Box 400)
    - Annual Reports 1951-58 (Box 400)
    - Boys Bureau, Bureau for Men and Boys, 1931-48 (Box 400)
    - Youth Bureau and Predecessors: (Box 401)
      - General I, 1950-57; II, 1957-59; III, 1959-60 (Box 401)
      - Handbooks of Bureau for Men and Boys 1946-49 (Box 402)
      - Intake Studies 1932-49 (Box 402)
      - Joint Application Bureau 1931 (C.O.S.) to 1943 (Box 402)
      - Predecessors: Miscellaneous, 1935-50 (Box 402)
      - Residence Facility (Proposed) for Young Offenders (Box 402)
      - Residences: Boys House 1941-60 (Box 402)
      - Residences: Boys House Buildings 1945-51 (Box 403)
      - Residences: Dosoris (for Girls) (Box 403)
      - Residences: Manual on House Cases (Box 403)
      - Residences: A Study of Boys' Needs for Residences 1939 (Box 403)
      - Studies: Boys Bureau and Dept. of Welfare, 1940-42 (Box 403)
    - Youth Counsel Bureau, Inc. 1942 (Box 403)
    - Youth Gangs; Chelsea-Lowell District and Lower East Side Neighborhood Association. (Box 403)
    - Youth and Justice: "The Legal Process in the Handling of Offenders in New York" Preliminary Draft of "Youth in the Toils", by Harrison and (the late) Grant, MacMillan, 1938. (Box 403)
  - Subseries XIV.2: Reports, Pamphlets, Pictures 1939-1960
    - Adolescents Unattached: (Box 404)
      - Boys Bureau - The First Ten Years 1931-41 (Box 404)
      - Boys House, An Evaluation of the Second, 1950 (Box 404)
      - Club-Residences and Room Registries, a Study of Residence Needs of Unattached Boys, 1939 by Subcommittee of the Bureau for Men and Boys (Box 404)
      - A Few Lives, a Report of Dosoris, Study and Treatment Home for Adolescent Girls, 1945-47 by Aileen Burton 1948 (Box 404)
      - A Study of Youth Bureau of the CSS of NY by the CSS Institute of Welfare Research, 1959 (Box 404)
      - Survey of Unmet Needs of Unattached Adolescents in NYC by Emanuel Hallowitz, 1955 (Box 404)
      - Twenty-One Residents of Boys House & Dosoris by Ruth Brenner, 1954 (Box 404)
      - Youth Bureau, Report by John Boyd, 1954 on Miss Coursey's Study; and Youth Bureau, Studies of Practice, Part II, by Patricia Coursey, 1953. (Caution: Contains Real Names) (Box 404)
    - Aging:
      - Aging, Family Health Series Guide for Public Health Nurses No. 8, 1948 and The Aging by Kathryn Rummel, 1959 (Box 404)
      - Budget Standards for Aging Persons, 1956 (Box 404)
      - Experimental Research in Social Work, Three Papers Presented at National Conference on Social Welfare May, 1959 (Box 404)
      - Foods for Health as We Grow Older 1949 (Box 404)
      - Old Age Study Project, Blenkner and Jahn 1956 (Box 405)
      - Old Age Study Project, Report of First Year, 1950 Wilma Winnick; and Digest (Box 405)
      - Old Age and Survivors' Insurance Referral Project 1959 (Box 405)
      - A Psychiatric Approach to Institutional Work With the Aged, Minutes of a Seminar, 1955 (Box 405)
    - Annual Reports of CSS, Unbound, 1939-49; 1949-60; Other Reports (Box 405)
    - Bulletin of CSS from April 17, 1939 (Merger) Through December 1959 #1 to 600, Mounted in 37 Folders (a Few Missing) 1939-1951 (Box 406)
    - Bulletin of CSS 1952- 1959 (Box 407)
    - Case Record Use Study, Longitudinal, for New Cases Opened May 1951 by Institute of Welfare Research 1953 (Box 407)
    - Cases, New see in Take (Box 407)
    - Cases That Return After First Closing, A Study of, by Kogan and Brown of I.W.R. 1958 (Box 407)
    - Casework, Method and Process in Social, Report of Staff Committee, 1958 (Box 407)
    - City Employees and Consumer Credit, Study Requested by Queens District, by Walter Kuzmich 1942 (Box 407)
    - Clippings from the Press 1945, 1947 (a few) 1945-53 (Destroyed per Memo 3/4/64), 1954, 1955, 1957, 1958, 1959 Miscellaneous V.V.O. one envelope AICP & COS; one COS 1882-1899 (Box 408-410)
    - Clippings: Nutrition, 1949, 1959 (outsize) (Box 408-410)
    - Community Service Society Program and Resources, by Robert T. Lansdale 1942 (Box 411)
    - Components of Movement (Studies 1951 '54, *57) see in Movement Consumer Credit (Not Found 7/81) (Box 411)
    - Consumer Credit Handbook, 1943 by Ward Stalnaker (Box 411)
    - Courts and Correction:
      - Attempts at Family Court Reform in New York City 1956-57, etc., Bernard C. Fisher "Working Papers" (Box 411)
      - Chaos in Sentencing Youth Offenders, by Leonard V. Harrison 1943 (Box 411)
      - Correctional Treatment of Youthful Offenders, by Leonard V. Harrison 1944 (Box 411)
      - Judicial Conference on Modernization of the Court Structure in New York State, 1958 (Box 411)
      - Justice for Youth, by Bernard C. Fisher 1955 (Box 411)
      - Manhattan Family Court Project 1956-58 (Box 411)
      - For the Family in Court, by Bernard C. Fisher 1956 (Box 411)
      - Five States, a Study of the Youth Authority Program as Promulgated by the American Law Institute, by Bertram M. Beck 1951 (Box 411)
      - A New Pattern for Family Justice, Bureau of Public Affairs, 1954 (Box 411)
      - Preventing Criminal Careers, by Leonard V. Harrison 1941 (Box 411)
      - Prisons Costs Too Much, by Leonard V. Harrison with William V. Vargish 1942 (Box 412)
      - Thirty-Seven Court Referrals, by Bertram M. Beck 1951 (Box 412)
      - While Children Wait, by Bertram M. Beck 1949 (Box 412)
      - A Year's Work for Justice, by Committee on Criminal Courts Of COS 1933 (Box 412)
      - The Youth Court Proposal, A Dissent 1955 (Box 412)
      - Youth Within Walls, by Bertram M. Beck 1950 (Box 412)
    - Cultural Problems in Social Casework,by Elise de la Fontaine et al (Box 412)
    - Direct Treatment of Children in a Family Agency, a Seminar by Dr. Sidney L. Green, 1953 Summarized 1955. 42pp. (Box 412)
    - Dosoris 1945 a Scrap Book (tooled leather) Presented by Mrs. Harold T. White 1960 (Includes Photos) (Box 412)
    - Emergency Employment Committee, New York City, Report October 1, 1930 - July 1, 1931 Emergency Employment Committee, Formation requested by AICP and COS (Box 412)
    - Employment Service, How Will They Get Work Now? by Emilie T. Strauss, 1943 (Box 412)
    - Family Service Agency, Scope and Methods see Scope (Box 412)
    - Family Service Department - Educational Nursing consultant Plan, a Study of by Sophia M. Robison, 1952 (Box 412)
    - Family Study, The, by Elise de la Fontaine, Caroline Falls (Box 412)
    - Marianne Homey (Study of the Family in Relation to Sickness and Health Care) 1940 Discussion (Box 412)
    - Family Service Case Survey, Institute of Welfare Research 1960 - 61, Reports 1-7 & 8-18 (Box 413)
    - Family Service Statistics (Box 413)
    - Analysis of, 1939-42 (Box 413)
    - Handbook for Caseworkers, 1950 see Statistics Handbook (Box 413)
    - Few Lives, A re; Dosoris, 1948 see Adolescents (Box 413)
    - Field Work of Students, evaluating the, see Students (Box 413)
    - Frontiers in Human Welfare, 1848-1948 The Story of a Hundred Years of Service to the Community of New York, CSS 1948 (Box 413)
    - Fund Raising Brochure: "Four in One" 1950 (Box 413)
    - Growth and Development of Italian Children in New York City, AICP 1924 (Box 413)
    - Guideposts for a Second Century of Community Service, a Synopsis of the Symposia Marking the Hundredth Anniversary, by Bertram Beck (unsigned) 1948? (Box 413)
    - Health Reports and Other Health Publications (heading, no Folder): (Box 414)
      - Evaluation of Service to 658 Families, Department of Educational Nursing 1949, 1951 (Box 414)
      - Experiment in the Control of Tuberculosis Among Negroes, by Jean Downes, Milbank Memorial Fund 1956 (Box 414)
      - Family Health Maintenance Demonstration: Proceeding of a Round Table, Milbank Memorial Fund 1954 (251pp) (Box 414)
    - Family Health Series: Guides for Public Health Nurses
      - Cardiac Conditions 1946 (Box 414)
      - Child Care and Development 1953, 1959 (Box 414)
      - Diabetes Mellitus 1941 (Box 414)
      - Fun for the Family 1949 (Box 414)
      - The Health Examination 1947 (Box 414)
      - Posture 1947 (Box 414)
      - Some Parasitic Infections Affecting Man 1957 (Box 414)
      - Syphilis 1947 (Box 414)
      - Tuberculosis 1956 (rev.) 1942 M3, M 6 (Box 414)
      - Photos, 1914 outsized (Box 414)
    - Family Health Service, a Study of the Department of Educational Nursing by Margaret Shetland 1943 (170pp.) (Box 414)
    - Family Medical Care a Report on the Family Health Maintenance Demonstration (1950-58) by George A. Silver, Harvard University Press 1963 (hardcover, 359pp.) (Box 414)
    - Follow-Up Study of Patients Given Health Examinations by the Department of Educational Nursing, Kogan and Weber mimeo 1951 (Box 414)
    - Gross Dental Needs in 324 Public-Health-Nursing-Service Families 1954 (Box 414)
    - Handbook of Information on Home Management for CSS Public Health Nurses 1953 (Box 414)
    - Health Work for Mothers and Children in a Colored Community AICP 1924 (Box 414)
    - Mulberry Health Center (AICP) 1919-23 (Box 414)
    - Some Observations on the Health Problems of CSS Families, Bruce Webster, M.D. 1940 (Box 415)
    - Health Nursing:
      - Bag and Thermometer Techniques - Photos Annotated for PHNs when Teaching Families (Box 415)
      - Child Care - Photos Annotated for Use of PHNs in Education Families ca. 1948 (Box 415)
      - Health Examinations, Men, Photos in Album outsized (Box 415)
      - Health Examinations, Women, Photos with Captions Loose in Large Red Envelope, outsized (Box 415)
      - Health Examinations, Women, Pictures in Red Album outsized (Box 415)
      - Intestinal Parasites: Have you Met the Parasite Family? Mildred Chapman, D.E.N. 1951 (Box 415)
      - "Keep Well" Photo Series ca. 1948 Outsized, in Last Drawer Beneath Reports (Box 415)
      - Play - Photos with Pamphlet "Fun for the Family" 1949 (Box 415)
      - Maternity Service: Serving the Maternity Patient Through Family-Centered Public Health Nursing, 1958-61 Shyne, LeMat, Kogan, 1962 (Box 415)
      - Patients Discharged or Transferred from the Geriatric Rehabilitation Service of Goldwater Memorial Hospital During 1958, 1959 and 1960. 1960 (Box 415)
      - Study of Twenty-Eight Months of Service Given by a CSS Public Health Nurse, Pearl Miles, R.N., 1952 (Box 415)
      - Time Spent in Direct Service to 89 Families by East River Public Health Nurses 1955 (Box 415)
      - Health - Tuberculosis (Box 415)
      - TB, Family Health Series Photos, Annotated, outsized (Box 415)
      - The Home Hospital Experiment (AICP) 1912-1914 (Box 415)
      - Tuberculosis Among Negroes, four Papers by Jean Downes et al, 1942-50 (Box 415)
      - Tuberculosis - A.M.A. Certificate of Honor 1909 (Box 415)
    - History:
      - Frontiers in Human Welfare: 1848-1948 The Story of a Hundred Years of Service to the Community of New York CSS 1948 (Box 415)
      - Growth and Development of AICP and COS, Lilian Brandt, Institute of Welfare Research 1942 (Box 415)
      - History of the Charity Organization Society of New York from 1882-1935 Ruth Scannell (Box 415)
      - The New York School of Social Work 1898-1941 Saul Bernstein et al, Institute of Welfare Research 1942 Homeless Man, Study of the, Draft 1938 (Box 416)
    - Homemaker Service - Extended, Project Reports 1954 ‘56, ‘58 (Box 416)
    - Housing Reports (Including Urban Development):
      - Adjusted Rents 1940 (Box 416)
      - Apartment Rooming-House Survey, Supplement to Life in One Room 1941 (Box 416)
      - Cellars and Basements, A Digest of Multiple Dwelling Law as It Relates to, and Criticism Thereof A. Dunham 1945 (Box 416)
      - Clearance and Redevelopment of Obsolescent Areas, 1939 a Report Submitted to City Planning Commission (Box 416)
      - Entrance to Home, A Report on Lighting of Public Halls in Tenement Houses 1941 (Box 416)
      - Fifty Years of Action on the Housing Front, John C. Hill 1948? (Box 416)
      - Forty Years of Housing, the Story of the Tenement House Committee of the COS 1938 and Through Forty Years, 1938? pub. by COS (Box 416)
      - Gold Medal Award to Tenement House Com. of COS for Models and Plans of Tenement 1901 (Box 416)
      - Grace Chapel Area, a Social Study of Census Tract #34 1941 (Box 416)
      - Greenwich Village; Observed Social Trends 1945 (Box 416)
      - Housing Information, a Periodical January 1940 - March 1949 (Box 416)
      - Housing Legislation in New York State Summarized 1959,X58, A57, *56, *52, and *51, 1945-1950 1939-43, seven Folders (Box 417)
      - Housing Regulation in War Time (1941 or 42?) (Box 418)
      - How Rent Control Works for You, by CSS et Alia 1944 (Box 418)
      - Keep Out the Invader, A Memorandum on the Need for Making Multiple Dwellings Ratproof 1941 (Box 418)
      - Kips Bay Neighborhood Study 1943 (Box 418)
      - Legislative Reports 1940-45 (Box 418)
      - Let the Sun In 1941 (Box 418)
      - Life in One Room 1940 (Box 418)
      - Major Housing Programs, Laws, and Agencies 1959 (Box 418)
      - Master City Plan proposed 1939 Statement to City Planning Commission by Committee Attorney Frederick Beebe (Box 418)
      - Minimum Standards for Family Dwellings 1945 (Box 418)
      - Miscellaneous COS Pamphlets (Box 418)
      - Multiple Dwelling Law: Administration of 1946 Enforcement of, 1946-47 (Box 418)
      - Multiple Dwelling Law, a Clarification 1945 (Box 418)
      - Not Without Hope, A Report and Recommendations on Family Relocation 1958 (Box 419)
      - Old Law Tenements, Twenty-Seven Suggestions for Improving 1939 (Box 419)
      - One-and-Two-Family Houses, "The Forgotten Ten Thousand" (3rd Draft 1950) (Box 419)
      - Pictures, Mainly from Europe - COS Tenement House Com. (Outsized, in Box) (Box 419)
      - Pictures of Model Houses for Workers, etc., from Hopedale, Mass. - COS Tenement House Com. (Outsize, in Box) (Box 419)
      - Providing for the Lowest Income Families in Housing Projects 1939 (Box 419)
      - Rehousing Needs of Families on Stuyvesant Town Site 1944, 1945 (Box 419)
      - Relocation of Residential Site Tenants 1956 (Box 419)
      - Rent Practices in Family Agencies 1941 (Box 419)
      - Safeguarding Ill-Housed Families 1939, 1940 (Revised) (Box 419)
      - The Slums New York Forgot - Substandard One-and-Two-Family Houses, a Study, 1950-51; Recommendations for Regulation, September 1953 The Facts and What to Do About Them, 1953 (Box 419)
      - The St. Marks Neighborhood, a Study of Housing and General Property Conditions in a Congested Area 1941, Revised 1943 (Box 419)
      - Taft Site Report, A Study of Site Tenants Potentially Eligible for Public Housing 1960 (Box 419)
      - They Live Underground, a Survey of Cellar Dwellings COS 1939 They Still Live Underground CSS 1940 (Box 419)
      - Through 40 Years, a History of the COS Tenement House Com., later Housing Com., 1938? (Box 419)
      - Toward Lower Cost Housing COS 1938 (Box 419)
      - Wagner-Ellender Housing Bill, Report on, 1945 (Box 419)
    - Intake, A Study of - New Cases Coming to Family Service During March, 1947 Blenkner, Hunt, and Kogan, Institute of Welfare Research 1950 (Box 420)
    - Intake Study 1941 see Queens (Box 420)
    - Longitudinal Case Record Use Study for New Cases Opened May 1951 Report I: May-November 1951 Report II: December 1951-May 1952 see Case Record Use (Box 420)
    - Manual on Judging Movement in Clients of Social Casework, Hunt, J. McV., et al, Institute of Welfare Research 1950 (Box 420)
    - Method and Process in Social Casework, Report of Staff Com. 1958 see Casework Method (Box 420)
    - Measuring Movement in Casework, J. McV. Hunt (Reprint, Journal of Social Casework 11/48) (Box 420)
    - Measuring Results in Social Casework, a Manual on Judging Movement, Hunt and Kogan, IWR 1950 (Box 420)
    - Movement, Definition and Scale for Rating, J. McV. Hunt et al, IWR, 1946-47 (Box 420)
    - Movement, A Study of the Components of, 117 pp & Appendix 59 pp. 1957 Ann W. Shyne and Leonard Kogan, IWR; Summary Article 3 pp. 1957 Prior Reports 1951, 1954 (Box 420)
    - Narcotics, The Problem of, in New York City - Leonard V. Harrison 1951 (Box 420)
    - Nutrition Education, Influence of in Families of Mulberry Area of NYC, Bovee & Downes 1941 (Box 420)
    - Nutrition: 14-Day Diet 1949 5-Day Diet, 1959 (See Clippings, Outsize in Box) (Box 420)
    - Observations of Non-Problem Children in the Playroom of Queens District Office, Fitzherbert and Mahler 1943 Vols. I & II (Caution to Confidentiality: Real Names in Text) (Box 420)
    - Pamphlets, Miscellaneous, From Related Organizations (Box 421)
    - Playroom Interviews Used for Preventive Mental Hygiene in Family Casework, a Queens District Study, Fitzherbert and Wolf 1948 (Box 421)
    - Positions in Social Work, Edward T. Devine and Mary VanKleeck, N.Y.School of Philanthropy - Pamphlet 1916 (Box 421)
    - Probation Bureau, Joint Report on, by Mayor's Committee on Juvenile Delinquency and CSS Committee on Youth and Justice, June 1944 and Related Reports (Box 421)
    - Queens District Playroom Study, see Observations of Non-Problem Children (Box 421)
    - Queens Intake February 1941 (Box 421)
    - Reporter of the BMB - Bureau for Men and Boys Periodical 1935-40 (Probably for Committee and Staff) (Box 421)
    - Relief Practices, Report on Survey of 1940 (Box 421)
    - Scope and Methods of the Family Service Agency (Box 421)
    - Sea Breeze - Role of Summer Camp for Mothers and Children in the CSS Program, an NYSSW Student Project 1951 (Box 421)
    - Short-Term Cases at the Community Service Society of N.Y. Leonard S. Kogan, IWR 1957 (140 pp. & Two Appendices) (Box 421)
    - The Short-Term Case in the Family Agency - Shyner, Kogan & Wasser - Family Service Association of America Reprint 1957 (Box 421)
    - Simple Arithmetic About Complex Children, A Study of Temporary Shelter Facilities for New York City's Children - Bertram M. Beck, 1952 (Box 422)
    - Smallest Democracy, For the - Gifford Fosdick, Belmont, et al 1939-40 (Box 422)
    - Social Studies Project in Private Schools - in Cooperation with Parents' League 1939-40 (Box 422)
    - Social Work Practice in a Family Agency, Papers from CSS Professional Conference 1958 Reprinted from Social Casework 1959 (Box 422)
    - Staff Newsletter: What’s Going On 1956-59 (Box 422)
    - Statistical Recording and Reporting in Family Welfare Agencies, Helen A. Fisk; 1934 (Box 422)
    - Students, Evaluating the Field Work of, by Rosemary Reynolds, FSAA Pamphlet 1946 (Box 422)
    - Study of the Youth Bureau of the CSS 1959 see Adolescents, Unattached (Box 422)
    - Testing Results in Social Casework, a Field Test of the Movement Scale, Hunt, Blenkner & Kogan, FSAA 1950 (Box 422)
    - Twenty Truants Under Care of Family Service 1945 (Unfinished?) (Box 422)
    - Urban Development, see Housing (Box 422)
    - Vacation Services - Camp Photos by W.H. Matthews 1941 Others 1951 - (Outsize) (Box 422)
    - Volunteers for Family Service, Chapter V by CSS Staff Member, FWAA 1942 (Box 422)
    - Ward Manor - Enlarged Photos of Two Main Houses, Water Color of Gate House (Outsize Box) (Box 422)
    - While Children Wait (Box 422)
    - Youth, see Adolescents (Box 422)
    - Youth and Correction - Chaos in Sentencing Youth Offenders 1943 et al, see Courts and Correction (Box 422)
  - Subseries XIV.3: Photographs, Overzize Materials, Books
    - Photographs: (Box 423)
      - Album, Camp, 1941 (Box 423)